hello everybody and welcome to a brand
new video today I'm going to be going
over ten bad habits of flipping now
these were pulled from my own
experiences so before I call me a
hypocrite be aware that I know already
hopefully you can learn a bit and find
something useful from these ten points
and let's get started
so these aren't in any particular order
but starting off at number one is
probably the most concrete one easy one
to fix that is undercutting now
unfortunately this is something I get
caught doing a lot I try not to do it on
higher volume items but for slower items
the stuff that really has not a lot
traded per day I tend to undercut the
person so undercutting is bad for high
volume margins and for slower items as
well however it does affect the high
volume margins quite a bit more if you
imagine an item only as a ten GP margin
if everyone undercuts it by 1 GP that
margin is gone probably was him four or
five people however if we consider a
100k item was a 20k margin people are
only undercutting by a 5 or 10 GP it's
not as big a deal plus the items just
coming a lot slower so I think it's a
little bit more fair to undercut on
slower items however I get caught
undercutting on high-volume items as
well now I think the main reason I've
got I gotten into this bad habit is one
of my videos are time-based so I feel a
pretty large pressure just to make
successful flips with him let's say my
when our challenges but that's not
really a good excuse bad for the margins
is bad for pretty much everyone in total
just be patient and match the offer
alright next up is trying to find hidden
flips now I find myself doing this quite
a bit I spend lots of time trying to
find items I think nobody would think
about finding them was a good margin I
put the offer in there and it sits for
like days now after all that time I do
end up profiting usually however usually
wasn't made a lot more if I just kept it
simple and pick some items that while
everyone probably knows about the art
good for a reason and will still yield
pretty good results and a lot quicker so
items like arches rings fury stuff like
that they still work really well even
though a lot of people know about them
obviously comes down to your personal
preference but if you're looking to make
the most money money in the shortest
amount of time
these simple items tend to work better
come on in number three is that trying
to guess item margins so I see a lot of
people just trying to guess the margins
between the items for like really high
volume items like archers rings and
stuff like that where you're much better
off just price second item in
sloop I insult one so you know exactly
what the margin looks like now it's
gonna save you a lot of time and it
won't lose you too much money obviously
you don't want to do this for items like
a twisted bomb or something that it's
better to guess it because you could
Stan's lose quite a bit of money on that
however for more average flippers and
people doing more everyday items you
should just price check one item so you
know exactly what it's that instead of
just wasting a bunch of time trying to
guess it come in at number four is the
stick two items with the most profit I
find that this weird mentality that once
I flipped an item I tend to want to move
on to another one just trying to
diversify this might have something to
do is trying to make my videos more
interesting but for the average player
if you find the item that works really
well just keep doing it there's no
reason to stop unless the margin goes
away or you start losing money or
something but barring that you should
really just run the item into the ground
there's no reason not to just for the
sake of having a nice or looking kind of
change history or something like that
coming in at number five is don't put
all your eggs into one basket now this
feels a little bit opposite to the last
point however what I mean by this is
don't invest every single penny into the
exact same item because if you do happen
to lose money on it you will stand to
lose quite a bit diversifying this is
always going to be safer for those who
don't want to take really larger risk
I'm not saying that you can't continue
to do the same item over and over again
as I mentioned in point number four
however it should not be your entire
capital invested into that one item come
in at number six is not paying attention
to runescape updates now would you tend
to read most of the updates but
oftentimes I don't really think of them
critically and how they would actually
affect items or items I even are
investing in right now taking the time
to look at the OSR s update is pivotal
if you want to do investment also if you
have certain items that you're not using
that are part of an update and you think
they're gonna drop in price it's better
to sell them off or just invest in a
separate item instead this one's not
pivotal although it's something that I
find myself wishing that I was paying
more attention to coming at number seven
is something I do quite a bit and that
leaving offers in when you leave for a
long period of time now there is certain
circumstances where you might want to do
this see my like 100-count flipping
series some items are going to be pretty
safe to leave offers in for weeks and
weeks on end however what I'm more
talking about is literally just starting
to do some flips and then forgetting
about them and then coming back a week
later to see that you have bought every
single one of those item any of since
dropped in price I'm not saying this
can't cage
work out however it's definitely not
worth it either you're going to not buy
any items or you're gonna buy all of
them and lose money coming in number
eight is being afraid to take risks now
you shouldn't have a risky investment
for every single one of your items
however there's no reason not to have
like five or ten percent of your money
invested into riskier investments or
higher margin flips or stuff you're not
quite sure about as you probably heard a
lot high risk investments tend to yield
high rewards but also higher losses so
that's why I wouldn't recommend
investing all your money in that but I
think everyone should be risk tolerant
enough to at least have a portion of
their money invested into riskier items
coming in number nine is flipping
brand-new items now again this can work
out if you know what you're doing but
more often than not people who buy brand
new items are set to pretty much lose
money almost always when new items are
released they are in a constant state of
crashing for usually almost a week or
two before the actual prices kind of
determined so if you're actually trying
to flip those items you have to be very
careful and in my experience honestly
it's just not really worth flipping on
day one it can work out but you really
have to pick items where you think that
their value is actually going to end up
higher or you just have to be very
careful how you flip the items because
you have to really lowball the offers
because it's constantly declining and so
there's a way to do it but overall I
just wouldn't really recommend it too
much and coming in number 10 is actually
probably the most important one that I'm
kind of coming to realize recently and
that is not being patient for me this
has really come down to doing videos
with time restrictions it really has
killed my patience obviously you don't
want to leave items in four days on days
on end you do need to cut your losses
sometimes however just having a little
bit of patience can really pay off even
for higher volume flips just waiting and
maybe going just taking a coffee break
or doing something coming back and you
know put a bit more money than just
always cutting your losses as soon as an
item stops buying or some margin gets
cut all these tips I'd say being patient
is probably the most important and vital
to being successful at flipping anyway
guys that is about it hope you enjoyed
the video do you want to see more kind
of videos like this feel like I do have
a couple more ideas for top ten ideas or
things you shouldn't be doing anyway if
you did enjoy it don't forget to leave
it a like and I will see you in the next
one